Just like my photography teacher used to say,
正如我的摄影老师常说的：
“We can teach you processes,
我可以教你怎么去拍
but we can’t teach you how to see.”
但是不能教你怎么用眼睛去看
Either you have some capacity to do that ….
或者你需要有这样的能力去观察
Then we'll say, spiritually, the reason (a disciple)
下面我们将谈到灵性的角度
you make connection with the Guru
与Guru(灵性导师）建立连结的原因
is to get the eyes to see;
是能获得那样的“ 眼睛”
to get to be initiated into subjective seeing.
能进入到主观情境
I’ll give you an example from another one of my teachers,
再举个例子，我的另一个老师
my biology teacher.
我的生物学老师
He announced, on the first day of class,
第一天，他在课堂上就宣布
you know the story? Anyway ….
你们听过这个故事吗？总之。。。
He announced on the first day of class, he said,
他在第一次上课的时候说：
“I’m going to teach you biology in such a way
我会用一种方式教你们生物-----这门学科
as when you wake up in the morning you’re going to see biology,
你们早上起床，会发现“生物学”无处不在
when you brush your teeth
当你们刷牙时，会看到它
when you eat your breakfast, you’re going to see biology,
当你们吃早餐时，会遇见它
when you go to the bathroom you’re going to see biology.
当你们去卫生间时，会看到它
And he was right.
他是对的
When we started hearing from him and his concepts,
当我们开始聆听他的授课
when you went to the bathroom,
去卫生间
when you ate your breakfast.
吃早餐的时候
Ṛṣi comes from the sanskrit word ‘dṛśi’,
Rishi  (圣哲）这个词来自于梵文的“drishti"
which means ‘to see’, ‘to observe’.
意味着去看，去观察
So a real spiritual agent is an observer of subjective reality.
一个真正的灵性代理人（灵性导师）是主观现实的观察者
This is what a Guru is: jñāninas tattva-darśinaḥ (Bg: 4.34);
这正是Guru的含义
an observer of subjective reality.
主观现实的观察者
And as Śrīla Guru Mahārāj will say,
Guru maharaj 说：
and from that plane, what they’ve observed
他们的观察，在那个平面
is passing through their consciousness to you
是通过他们的意识到达你那里
in the form of mantram or revelation.
以曼陀罗或者心灵启示的方式
Then putting yourself under the guidance of such an agent,
把自己放在灵性代理引导下的位置
you’re now in connection with revealed truth
你现在和真理的揭示有了连结
as opposed to objective truth; objectively verifiable things
和客观真理相反，这是绝对的可验证的事实
which are just agreed upon.
一个大多数同意
It’s a consensus of agreed upon norms of this world
这个世界约定俗称的规范
if we say ‘kilometres’ or ‘miles’.
当我们说：公里或英里
Spiritual agents.
灵性的代理人
Prabhupād’s favorite expression: ‘transparent via medium’;
帕布帕德最喜欢的表达：显然，他们是媒介
they’re mediums, they’e curating a spiritual experience.
他们是将灵性体验传达给我们的媒介
So, what they’ve observed in the subjective world,
因此，他们在主观世界有所洞察
they’re the agents or the medium
他们是代理或媒介
for expression of that in the objective world.
将主观世界的察觉呈现于客观世界
So, depending upon their ‘locus standi’ or their GPS, where they're located
所以，根据他们所在的位置，他们的全球定位系统
in terms not only geographically, but historically,
不仅从地理方位，甚至历史的角度
they’ll find the ways and means amongst that population,
他们能找到适合那个群体的手段
where they're situated,
他们的程度
to translate revealed truth into something
去解释启示的真理
that’s accessible to the local people.
对于那里的人是容易接受的
You may not need to understand, let’s say, art.
其实你并不需要明白，让我们谈谈艺术
—the substantial, the higher stuff—
更本质，更高成色的
keep exposing you to that,
将自己继续置身于此
giving you some education along the way,
会在这个过程中给你很多培养
and the day will come where you’ll have an epiphany
这样有一天会顿悟
and what they see: you’ll be seeing that.
他们看到的 ，你也将看到
That's why the Vedas, Guru Mahārāj said, it said,
Guru Maharaj 说
“It’s not as important to understand me. Keep hearing.”
理解我所说的并不是最重要的，继续聆听
Like we sing the songs every day,
就像我们每天唱颂的歌
we hear certain ślokas every day over and over again;
我们一遍又一遍听到某些slokas(圣典中的诗歌）
“Keep hearing”.
继续聆听
We read Gītā over and over again
我们一遍又一遍阅读梵歌
and then at a certain time through ….
在特定的时间从头到尾
And here, we add service.
在这里我们做服务
You can’t be antagonistic or envious of the teacher,
你不能抗拒或是嫉妒
or the agent, in the spiritual life.
你的老师，或者灵性生活的代理人（guru）
In the material world you might despise your teacher,
在俗世，你也许轻视自己的老师
and get the knowledge or the information.
和获得的知识、信息
Spiritually, that doesn’t work.
从灵性的角度这不成立
when a child goes to school you tell them,
当一个小孩儿去学校，你告诉他：
“Put full faith in your teacher here.”
全心全意地信任你的老师
And I know my own experience,
我的经历是
the first nun I had—Sister Paul ….
我的第一个幼儿班老师---修女paul
Sister Paul’s our teacher;
她是我们的老师
we believe everything she says
我们相信她说的每一句话
without hesitation, without doubt, without suspicion.
没有犹豫，没有疑惑，没有怀疑
So the transmission is very rapid
所以知识和信息会很快的传递
because of that depth of belief.
由于这深度的信任
Then, went to another grade, second and third grade,
之后升到另外一个年级，第二、三年级时
and Sister Paul wasn’t there,
Paul 并不在那儿
there was another sister.
有另外一个老师
And at first I was upset,
起初我很伤心
because I had so much faith in Sister Paul,
因为我太信任Paul 了
I couldn’t understand why she’s not teaching me.
我不能接受理解为什么她不再教我
Where’s my first grade teacher?
我的第一个老师呢？
They said, “No-no, she’ll be teaching you here.”
他们说：不，不， 她会是你的新老师
Then I learned to accept that teacher, give that faith.
然后我学习接受这个老师，给予她信任
And this is the way of progress.
这就是能进步的方法